In the previous lesson,
在上一节课
you learnt some techniques for manipulating data.
你学习了一些处理数据的技巧
In this lesson, you'll learn some additional functions and
在这节课 你将学习一些分析电子表格数据的
techniques useful for analyzing the data in your spreadsheet.
其他实用函数和技巧
What do we really mean when we say analyze the data?
分析数据到底是什么意思？
Well, we start with a lot of information about something, our data.
我们拥有关于某个内容的大量信息 即数据
Such as how many apples and oranges were ordered in the fruit stand example,
例如水果摊示例中 顾客购买了多少苹果和橘子
or rosters and salaries in the baseball players example.
或者棒球运动员示例中的球队阵容和薪资
This data by itself doesn't mean much
这些数据本身并没多少含义
until we start asking and answering questions about it.
直到我们开始对数据提出问题并回答问题
For example, how many pieces of fruit on average were in each order,
例如 每单平均有多少个水果？
or what's the average salary for an American League Baseball player in 2003?
或者 2003 年美国棒球联合会运动员的平均薪资是多少？
We can find out some of this information using aggregation functions.
我们可以使用聚合函数了解这些信息
You've already used two of these,
你已经使用了两个聚合函数
sum and average to answer some questions.
SUM 和 AVERAGE 来回答一些问题
So you've already started analyzing data
因此你已经在上一节课
with aggregation functions in the previous lesson.
开始使用聚合函数分析数据
There are quite a few more aggregation functions and you're going to learn some of these.
还有很多其他聚合函数 你将学习其中一些函数
These functions may not answer all the questions we have though.
但是这些函数可能并不能回答我们的所有问题
We often want to find out if a cell meets certain conditions.
我们经常想知道某个单元格”是否“满足特定的条件
For example, if a student scored above a certain value on a test give them an A.
例如 某位学生在测试中的得分 是否超出了特定值 是则打个 A
For these conditional dependencies,
对于这些条件
logical functions are what is needed.
我们需要用到逻辑函数
We'll go over the IF function and the comparison operators that go with it.
我们将讲解 If 函数以及相应的比较运算符
Then, examine logical functions And Or, and Not.
然后学习逻辑函数 And、Or 和 Not
The last group of logical functions we'll explore,
我们将学习的最后一组逻辑函数
combine aggregation with logic.
会将聚合函数与逻辑函数相结合
We refer to these as conditional aggregation functions.
我们将其称为条件型聚合函数
Next, you'll learn to create pivot tables.
接着 你将学习如何创建数据透视表
A pivot table is a tool that will allow you to
数据透视表将使你能够用一步
summarize and aggregate data all in one step.
来总结和汇总数据
After that, we'll shift directions a bit and introduce named ranges,
接着 我们将介绍已命名区域 (Named Ranges)
which are helpful when we reuse the same ranges over and over in our spreadsheets.
使我们能够在电子表格中重复利用相同的区域
It's much easier to remember something like, student roster,
记住 student roster
than some cryptic address like sheet3!A1:J943 or some such thing.
比一些奇怪的地址 例如 sheet3!A1:J943 要简单得多
Using descriptive names for ranges will also reduce errors and
使用描述性区域名称还可以减少错误
increase understanding of the formulas as they become more complex.
并且更容易理解变得更加复杂的公式
The named ranges are going to be especially helpful in working with lookup functions,
在这节课结尾时 当我们使用查找函数时
at the end of the lesson.
命名区域将很有用
Okay let's get started.
我们开始吧